Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Media Department records, 1961-1994 and undated RL.11688
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Media Department records
1961-1994 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11688
6.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The London Office first opened in 1899. Collection includes published media reports, corporate documentation, research reports, texts of presentations, correspondence, as well as casting and other production notes that document the Media Department's administrative operations as well as participation in creation of television advertising. Companies represented include BBC, British Telecom, Brooke Bond Oxo, Ford, Golden Wonder (now a subsidiary of Tayto), Kellogg, Kodak, McCann Erickson, Ogilvy & Mather; Rowntree, Scott Andrex (now part of Kimberly-Clark), St. Ivel (now part of Dairy Crest), Superchannel, Thames Television, TSB Bank, and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Account Files; Printed Material.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The London Office first opened in 1899.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Media Department records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. International advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Miles Colebrook papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. New Business records
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Print advertisements
Collection Overview
Collection includes published media reports, corporate documentation, research reports, texts of presentations, correspondence, as well as casting and other production notes that document the Media Department's administrative operations as well as participation in creation of television advertising. Companies represented include BBC, British Telecom, Brooke Bond Oxo, Ford, Golden Wonder (now a subsidiary of Tayto), Kellogg, Kodak, McCann Erickson, Ogilvy & Mather; Rowntree, Scott Andrex (now part of Kimberly-Clark), St. Ivel (now part of Dairy Crest), Superchannel, Thames Television, TSB Bank, and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Television advertising; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Brooke Bond Tea Company; Eastman Kodak Company; Ford Motor Company; Kellogg Company; Rowntree Mackintosh Ltd; Kimberly-Clark Corporation; Ogilvy & Mather; McCann-Erickson Worldwide; Young & Rubicam
- General Files, 1974-1993 and undated; 1
  - 1979 Television Planning Guide, 1978 (Box 1)
  - 1989/90 Domestic Energy Advertising, 1990 (Box 1)
  - A Glossary of Media Terms, 1986-1993; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - A Presentation on Cinema Markets and Media Facts in the U.K., France, Germany And Italy for United Artists, undated (Box 1)
  - A Presentation To David Sheilds, National Magazine Company, 1992 (Box 1)
  - A Review of U.K. Countline Market, 1990 (Box 1)
  - A Study of the Quality of Reading Amongst Women, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Advertising and the Funding of the BBC, 1985 (Box 1)
  - An Introduction to Media in the U.K., 1985 (Box 1)
  - "Best of the Month T.V." and "Best of the Rest Radio", 1990 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting agenda and notes, 1989; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Brands in Trouble (Julie Llesse), 1992 (Box 1)
  - Brian Beamish Music Consultant, undated (Box 1)
  - British Satellite Broadcasting, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Capital Advertising Research, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Children and Television, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Children's Hour, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Coexisting And Competing With Retail Brands, undated (Box 1)
  - Consumer Magazines, undated (Box 1)
  - Consumer Magazines Market Structure, undated (Box 1)
  - Cosmopolitan (sample issue and readership profile), 1992 (Box 1)
  - Developing And Protecting Core Brands: A Presentation to IPC, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Eaglemoss: Improving Media Performance in the 1990's (Box 1)
  - Efficiency Versus Effectiveness Media Considerations, undated (Box 1)
  - English Markell Pockett, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Esquire (sample issue), 1992 (Box 1)
  - Fresh Eggs and Flying Lessons (Jeremy Bullmore), 1974 (Box 1)
  - Henley Centre reports in food advertising, private/own labels, 1992 (Box 1)
  - House Beautiful (sample issue), 1992 (Box 1)
  - How To Sell: The Regional Press to Media People (Jeremy Nathan), undated (Box 1)
  - "How Will Advertising Rates Stand Up in 1986?", 1985 (Box 1)
  - JWT Board meeting, 1992 (Box 1)
  - JWT Europe/International work, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Means of data collection, undated (Box 1)
  - MediaTel keys, undated (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Second J. Walter Thompson Asia Pacific Media Forum, 1986; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - National Magazine Company Summary of Major Brands, 1992 (Box 1)
  - National Magazines Groups One and Two, undated (Box 1)
  - New Media: What to Look for in 1982 (Box 1)
  - Ogilvy and Mather Europe: The Television Guide, 1986 (Box 1)
  - OOORinger Advertising Primer, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Own-label Branding, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Own Label: Sleeping With The Enemy, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Pan European Satellite Television Summary of 1988 Plans, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Prima: The Dynamics of Communication, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Private Label: The Branded Manufacturer Challenge (OC&C Strategy Consultants), 1991 (Box 1)
  - Research into Magazine Reading, undated (Box 1)
  - Review of the TABS Technique, undated (Box 1)
  - Sainsbury own-label, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Satellite media information, 1988 (Box 1)
  - SESAME: What It Is and What It Does, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Short Units Risk-Responsibility-Reward, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Soundalikes: Nothing Compares to Us, undated (Box 1)
  - Sponsorship: JWT Europe Examples, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Television Department, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Tesco own-label, 1992 (Box 1)
  - The Australian Media Scene, 1982 (Box 1)
  - The Business Press in Europe, 1990 (Box 1)
  - The Cinema Handbook, 1993 (Box 1)
  - The Future for Old and New Television Channels in the U.K., 1989 (Box 1)
  - The Future of the Radio Industry: A Supplementary Submission of the IPA, 1986 (Box 1)
  - The Launch of Euro-Disney 1992, 1989 (Box 1)
  - The Media Landscape Now to 1995, 1987 (Box 2)
  - The Regional Investment of Television Budgets, 1978 (Box 2)
  - The United Kingdom Media Scene, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Tomorrow's Research, 1991 (Box 2)
  - U.K. Media Scene, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Using Europe's Business Press to reach Europe's decision makers, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Weighing the Balance: Advantages of Agency Media Service vs. In-House Media Operation, 1987 (Box 2)
  - What Are Children Eating These Days?, 1981 (Box 2)
  - "What Happens When I Get There?", 1992 (Box 2)
  - What Information Is Needed to Evaluate Flighting Patterns For T.V. Schedules?, 1989 (Box 2)
  - What's Happening in Media, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Women and Magazines, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Zenith Status Report, 1989 (Box 2)
- Account Files, 1983-1993 and undated; 2
  - British Telecom Television Buying Review, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Brooke Bond Foods Coolbrew July-October 1989 Summary of Media Schedule (Box 2)
  - Brooke Bond Foods OXO, 1983, 1990-1991; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Brooke Bond OXO artist's contracts, 1983-1988 (Box 2)
  - Ford--Evaluation of Ford Ski Report Campaign on Sky Channel, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder commercial correspondence, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps commercial information, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps "Moon Landing" correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps "Moon Landing" music and artistes, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps "Moon Landing" pre-production details, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps "Moon Landing" quotes, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps "Moon Landing" script, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps "Moon Landing" timing plan, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps--Steve Ovett, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg 1987 television negotiation strategy, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg Company of Great Britain Limited, 1988 Television Buying Review, 1989; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Kellogg Cost and Communication Efficiency of Variable Commercial Timelengths, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg "Hands Off" script, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg "Holiday" script, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg "Indecision" script, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg presentation to TVS, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg set designs, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg "Time's Up" script, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes commercial memos, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard", 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" casting, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" correspondence, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" music, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" pre-production, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" quotes, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" timing plan, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Bran Flakes "Cupboard" wardrobe, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies casting, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies pre-production meeting "Torpedo", 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies "Torpedo" :30, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies "Torpedo" correspondence, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies "Torpedo" pre-production details, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies "Torpedo" quotes, 1990; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies "Torpedo" timing plan, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Rice Krispies "Torpedo" wardrobe and set, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Variety adult casting, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Variety children casting, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Variety correspondence, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Variety pre-production notes, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg's Variety quotes, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Kellogg's Variety timing plans, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Kellogg's various scripts, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Kodak initial media proposals, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Kodak media material, undated (Box 3)
  - Kodak News, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Kodak Office Imaging Copy Products 1992 Press and Public Relations Programme (Box 3)
  - Kodak Office Imaging Market Communications Brief, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Listerine and Clifford: A Breathtaking Success, 1988 (Box 3)
  - National Westminster Bank (NatWest) commercial correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - National Westminster Bank commercial scripts, 1990 (Box 3)
  - National Westminster Bank "Kipper" commercial script, 1990 (Box 3)
  - National Westminster Bank pre-production details and creative background, 1990 (Box 3)
  - National Westminster Bank quotes, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - National Westminster Bank timing plan, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Pepsi: The Pepsi Challenge, 1986 (Box 3)
  - PepsiCo 1983 U.K. Challenge Activity Review (Box 3)
  - PepsiCo 1986/7 Advertising Development (Box 3)
  - Pepsi-Cola Carbonated Soft Drink Market Review, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Pepsi-Cola Media Proposals for 1987 (Box 3)
  - Pepsi television advertising, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Black Magic", 1990 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Black Magic" music correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Black Magic" scripts, 1987-1990 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Dairy Box" and "Black Magic" Alan Cluer and Associates correspondence, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Dairy Box" and "Black Magic" correspondence, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Dairy Box" and "Black Magic" pre-production meeting, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Dairy Box" and "Black Magic" quotes, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Dairy Box" and "Black Magic" timing plan, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Rowntree "Too Busy Thinking about My Baby" correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Scott Andrex casting, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex commercial material, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex detailed timing plan, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex "Forest", 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex "Forest" pre-production details, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Scott Andrex location details, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex "Market Garden" quotes, 1990; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex pre-production and correspondence, 1990; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex pre-production meeting, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex pre-production meeting "Forrest", 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex television commercial cost estimates, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex television commercials, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex timing plan and shoot information, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott Andrex VW and Land Rover, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Scott commercial details, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel "Balloon" The Mill quotation/estimate, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "Balloon" advertising, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "Balloon" call sheet, 1990 (Box 7)
  - St. Ivel Gold "Balloon" pre-production meeting, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "Balloon" television, cinema production estimate, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "Balloon" timing plan, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "Balloon" various, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold casting/music, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold pre-production notes, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold scripts/storyboards, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "The Beach", 1989 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold "The Beach" television, cinema production estimate, 1989 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel Gold various, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel "The Mill" quotation/estimate, 1990 (Box 3)
  - St. Ivel's Butter, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Superchannel--Gaining Distribution and Viewership for Superchannel, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Superchannel--Generating Advertising Revenue for Superchannel, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Swadders Ltd.: JWT U.K. media presentation, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Thames Television Summary of Recommendations, undated (Box 4)
  - TSB Loans "Theatre" pre-production details, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Wall's Sausages Light and Lean Range 1986 Media Launch Recommendations (Box 4)
- Printed Material (Reference Library), 1961-1994; 3
  - Australia's Media Scene (Hansen-Rubensohn/McCann-Erickson), 1970 (Box 4)
  - BBC Annual Report and Handbook, 1961-1985 (Box 5)
  - BBC Annual Report and Handbook, 1986-1992 (Box 4)
  - Brad Advertising and Agency List, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Eating in the Early 1980s (MRB International), 1984 (Box 4)
  - European Market and Media Fact (Zenith Media), 1991 (Box 4)
  - Focus Media and Marketing Guide (prepared by DMBB), 1985 (Box 4)
  - Focus Media and Marketing Guide (prepared by Saatchi & Saatchi), 1987 (Box 4)
  - Henley Centre--Currency Profiles Global Economic Forecasts, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - The IBA's Reference Book for Independent Broadcasting, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - ITV: Guide to Independent Television, 1963-1974 (Box 5)
  - Market Reports Service: Children and the Media, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Media and Marketing Europe, 1989-1990; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Media International, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
  - MediaFact U.K. Consumer Media Yearbook, 1988 (Box 4)
  - National Readership Survey Volume I, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Ogilvy--Developing the Media Strategy (W. Patterson), 1984 (Box 4)
  - Ogilvy--New Media in Europe Newsletter number 31, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Ogilvy--New Media in Europe Newsletter number 52, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Ogilvy--The Media Function in Advertising Planning, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Television and Radio, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Television and Radio, 1978-1988 (Box 6)
  - Time & Space (Y&R Media), 1986 (Box 4)